Preliminary Guide to the Jaroslav Hulka Papers, 1922-2003 and undated (bulk 1968-2000)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jaroslav Hulka papers 1922-2003 and undated (bulk 1968-2000)
Hulka, Jaroslav F.
36.5 linear feet Extent: 15465 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00589
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Box 42 is closed to research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jaroslav Hulka Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Biographical Note
Physician at the University of North Carolina and long-time supporter of women's reproductive rights; founding member of the UNC Population Center, pioneering OB/GYN, inventor/innovator of the Hulka Clip, laparoscopy, intrauterine devices and other medical apparatus and procedures.
Collection Overview
The collection consists largely of professional papers including subject and research files, correspondence, and writings. Materials pertain to Hulka's involvement in the education, promotion, innovation, and application of women's and reproductive health. Specific topics include laparoscopy, abortion rights, contraception, professional organizations, medical procedures, and educational materials. The collection also includes examples of medical instruments (some of which were developed and patented by Hulka), especially a variety of international IUDs and other forms of contraception including the eponymous "Hulka clip." Also contains drawings and photographs of surgical procedures; educational and presentation slides; blueprints of medical instruments; and correspondence and essays provided by colleagues and students. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Subject Headings
Hulka, Jaroslav F.; Women -- Health and hygiene -- North Carolina; Women's health services -- North Carolina; Physicians -- North Carolina; Obstetricians -- United States; Obstetricians -- Correspondence; Gynecologists -- United States; Gynecologists -- Correspondence; Abortion; Pregnancy; Obstetrics; Contraception; Contraceptive agents; Birth control; Abortifacients; Intrauterine contraceptives; Hysterectomy; Laparoscopy; Laparoscopic surgery; Surgical instruments and apparatus; Medical instruments and apparatus; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Slides; Videocassettes; Machine-readable records; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2003-0123
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - AAGL [American Association of Gynecologic Laparoscopists] 1997, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Foundation of AAGL, 1996-2001, n.d, (5 folders) (Box 1)
    - Trustees, 1996-2001, n.d, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - Papers Reviewed (Misc.), 1996-2001, n.d, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Editorial Board, 1996-2001, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Meeting of the Journal of the American Association of Gynecologic Laparoscopists 28th Annual Meeting, 1999 Nov. 10 (Box 2)
    - Credentials Committee 1995, 1991-1995, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - AAOE [American Association of Office Endoscopy], 1980-1996, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - American Medico-Legal Foundation, 1996 (Box 2)
    - ACGE [Accreditation Council for Gynecologic Endoscopy, Inc.], 1994-1998 (Box 2)
    - ACOG [American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists], 1997-1999 (Box 2)
    - ACOG, Semmelweis Epidemiologic Society, 1985-1992, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - SGI [Society For Gynecologic Investigation], 1996 Oct. 22 (Box 2)
    - American Fert. Society, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Society of Reproductive Surgeons, 1985-1988, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Falloppius International Society, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
    - SLS [Society of Laparoendoscopic Surgeons], 1997-1999 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Aquintel Inc., 1996-1997, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - IPI [Innovative Physicians Incorporated], 1991-1995, (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - Czechoslovakia Society of Arts and Science, 1992, Apr. 25 (Box 3)
    - Electroscope, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
    - IPI and Wolf, 1995 (Box 3)
    - IPI and Zimmer, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
    - Rotary, 1994 and 1998 (Box 3)
    - WHO [World Health Organization], 1994-1998 (Box 3)
    - NC Bar, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Wolf, 1996-2000, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Practical Training and Research in Gynecological Endoscopy: Meeting WHO - February, 19-22 1996, 1996, (1 binder and 1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Laparoscopy with Dr. H. Lefler, Jr. (#1), 1972 (Box 4)
    - Laparoscopy Teaching Packages, #1 (Notes), 1972-1975, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Basic Population Dynamics: A Self Instructional Program, #2, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Basic Population Dynamics, #2 (Notes), 1973, undated (Box 4)
    - The Infertile Couple: A Self-Instructional Program, #3, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Clip Instructions Residents Teaching, #5, n.d (Box 4)
    - Hulka Clip Instruction Manual, #5 (Notes), 1981-1982, n.d (Box 4)
    - MHCH 210-Maternal-Infant Health and Family Planning, 1983-1985, n.d (Box 4)
    - Anastomosis, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Stress Incontinence, #6, 1971-1989 (Box 5)
    - During the Infertility Survey..., 1980 (Box 5)
    - Laparoscopic Photography Paper-Olympus, 1981 and undated (Box 5)
    - Estimates of PID Induced Infertility in United States, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    - Sex Determination of Offspring and Timing of Artificial Insemination with Frozen Donor Semen, 1978 (Box 5)
    - American Association of Gynecologic Laparoscopists: Membership Surveys and Complications Reports, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Prospective study of 1973, Presented 1974, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - AAGL Membership Survey 1974, presented in November 1975, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 1975 AAGL Membership Survey, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - AAGL Survey 1975, presented in Nov. 1976, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - AAGL Survey 1976, presented Dec. 1977, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Complications Survey 1977, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - AAGL Survey 1977, Presented November 1978, 1977-1979 (Box 6)
    - AAGL Survey 1979, 1976-1983, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - AAGL Tubal Study Form (Original), 1977 and undated (Box 6)
    - Teaching Programs, 1970-1981, n.d (Box 6)
    - 1980 AAGL Survey, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - AAGL 1982 Survey, 1982-1984, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - 1982 AAGL Survey, 1980-1984 (Box 6)
    - AAGL 1983 Survey, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
    - AAGL 1984 Survey, 1983-1985 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - 1985 AAGL Survey, 1987 (Box 6)
    - The Development of Gynecologic Laparoscopy in Germany: A statistical review of the years 1989-1993, 1997 (Box 6)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 6)
    - April [AAGL Meeting], 1997 (Box 6)
    - May [AAGL Meeting], 1997 (Box 6)
    - AAGL Sept 27 Sterilization Update, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Mexico, FHI [Family Health International], July 14-16 1997, 1997 (Box 7)
    - AAGL Meeting Sept, 22-28 1997, 1997 (Box 7)
    - 1997 AAGL Survey, 1997 (Box 7)
    - AAGL Nov. 1997 Meeting [Loose Records], 1997 (Box 7)
    - Practical Training, Feb 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 7)
    - Trends in Women's Healthcare, March 9-11 1997, 1996-1997 (Box 7)
    - AAGL 25th Meeting Chicago Ill., Sept, 25-29, 1996, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Practical Training Oct. 1996, 1994-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - PRCH [Physicians for Reproductive Choice and Health], NYC, Nov. 11-12, 1996, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Women's Healthcare Conference, Nov, 18-19, 1996, 1996 (Box 7)
    - AAGL Trustees, Chicago, Nov. 23, 1996, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Abortion, 1969-1991, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - OP-ED Piece-(In Development), 1994-1998, undated (Box 8)
    - Atlanta Journal-Constitution Letters/Articles, 1994 (Box 8)
    - Wall Street Journal-Editorial Piece, 1994 (Box 8)
    - Essays on Abortion, 1998-1999, n.d (Box 8)
      [Loose records grouped together.]
    - Birth Control Costs, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - Abortion: Training of Physicians, 1993, Apr. 2 (Box 8)
    - Articles on Abortion, 1989-1990, undated (Box 8)
    - Medical Data, 1976-1991, undated (Box 8)
    - Abortion, 1975-1993, undated (Box 8)
    - Abortion Harassment Survey, 1992-1993, (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Articles on Abortion, 1994-1998, [Loose records] (Box 8)
    - Abortion 1995, 1994-1996, undated (Box 8)
    - Mefi Priston-RDU-486, Abortion 94, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Abortion, 1994 (Box 8)
    - Abortion Consent 1994, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
    - Abortion 1993, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
    - 1993 Abortion and Screening, 1992, Dec. 21 (Box 8)
    - ACC [Ambulatory Care Center] Abortion, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence Regarding Abortion, 1993 (Box 8)
      [Loose records]
    - Abortion Harrassment Law, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Abortion 1992, 1991-1993, undated (Box 8)
    - Abortion 1990, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
  - Contents of Box 9: (Box 9)
    - Policy and Ethics, 1977-1981 (Box 9)
    - Abortion 1989, 1987-1989, undated, (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Abortion 1987, 1959-1987 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 9)
    - Hulka 3rd ed., 1994-1999, (7 folders) (Box 9)
  - Contents of Box 10: (Box 10)
    - Hulka LAP I [textbook on laparoscopy], 1983-1985, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Hulka 2d Ed., 1990-1994, (8 folders) (Box 10)
    - History and Basic Sciences, #1, 1996 and undated (Box 10)
    - Optics and TV, #2, 1982-1996, undated (Box 10)
    - Power: electric/laser, #3, 1979-1995, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Gas/Pneumoperitoneum, #4, 1988-2000 (Box 10)
    - Wound Healing, #5, 1979-1994, undated (Box 10)
  - Contents of Box 11: (Box 11)
    - Facilities/Equipment, #6 (II. Basic Clinical Aspects), 1980-1996 (Box 11)
    - Nursing, #7, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Assessing Pt. [patient] Risk, #8, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Entry Abdominal/Closure, #9, 1990-1998 (Box 11)
    - Credentialling, #10, 1992-1998 (Box 11)
    - Anesthesia, #11, 1973-1999 (Box 11)
    - Sterilization, #12 (III Basic Gynecology), 1978-1999, (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Infertility, #13, 1974-1998 (Box 11)
    - Chronic Pelvic Pain, #14, 1977-1996 (Box 11)
    - Acute Pelvic Pain, #15, 1979-1995 (Box 11)
  - Contents of Box 12: (Box 12)
    - Persistent Adnexal, #16, 1968-2000, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - Endometriosis, #17, 1990-1995 (Box 12)
    - Consent, #18, 1983-1996 (Box 12)
    - Special require., #19 (IV Operative Gynecology), 1989-1997 (Box 12)
    - Low. Incisions/Repair. #20, 1990-1996 (Box 12)
    - Lysis of Adhesions, #21, 1987-1996 (Box 12)
    - Hemostasis, #22, 1991-1997 (Box 12)
    - Adnexal Surgery, #23, 1987-1996 (Box 12)
    - Ectopic Pregnancy, #24, 1991-1997 (Box 12)
    - Peritoneal Cavity Adhesiology, #25 (V. Advanced Gynecology), [empty folder] (Box 12)
    - Pelvic wall dissect., #26, [empty folder] (Box 12)
    - Using the Laparoscope for SUI [stress urinary incontinence], #27, 1980-1996, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Correction of Genital Prolapse, #28, 1995 and undated (Box 12)
    - Lap. hysterorectomy, #29, 1992-1999 (Box 12)
  - Contents of Box 13: (Box 13)
    - Office Laparoscopy, #30 (VI. GYN Controversies), 1995-1997 (Box 13)
    - Patient Assisted Laparoscopy, #31, 1996-2000 (Box 13)
    - Cul de sac Endometr., #32, 1922-1993 (Box 13)
    - Pelvic Abscess, #33, 1984-1995 (Box 13)
    - Myomectomy, #34, 1986-2000 (Box 13)
    - Endoscopy in Gyn. Onc., #35, 1992-1997 (Box 13)
    - Pelvic Lymphadenect., #36, 1990-1996 (Box 13)
    - Para-aortic lymph., #37, 1996-1997 (Box 13)
    - Cholecystectomy, #38 (VII. General Surgery), 1976-1998 (Box 13)
    - Herniorrhaphy, #39, 1992-1996 (Box 13)
    - Nissan Fundoplasty, #40, 1996 (Box 13)
    - Appendectomy, #41, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Emer. Room Laparosc., #42, 1991-1996 (Box 13)
    - Survey data: GYN, Sx, #43 (VIII. Complic.), 1990-1996 (Box 13)
    - Lap. Management, #44, 1994 (Box 13)
    - #45 [empty folder] (Box 13)
    - CPT-Appendix, #46, 1996-1997 (Box 13)
    - Jan 17 '98, JAAGL Meet., 1997-1998 (Box 13)
    - Jan 11 '98, Willard Hotel, 25 years ROE [Roe v. Wade], 1997-1998 (Box 13)
    - Wolf-Chicago, March 27, 1987-1997 (Box 13)
    - [Loose record re. Carolina Population Center fellows retreat.], 1997 (Box 13)
    - April 21-26 Las Vegas, FAAGL, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Teluride April 5-8 '98 [Trends in Women's Healthcare conference], 1998 (Box 13)
    - ACOG [American College of Obstetricians and Gyncologists] May 10-12 (Wolf Co.), 1995-1998 (Box 13)
    - Overtures-3, 1998 (Box 13)
    - NIH Sterilization, June 11-12, 1998, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Presby. Church, June 15-16, Charlotte, 1995-1998 (Box 13)
  - Contents of Box 14: (Box 14)
    - Chicago, JAAGL [and FAAGL], July 16-19, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9/28-29, Kansas City IPI, 1998 (Box 14)
    - Orlando MWHO, 10/8-9, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 10/1-10/4 Ross Society, Sea Island Georgia, 1998 (Box 14)
    - [Loose record re. Physicians for Reproductive Choice and Health], 1999 May 7 (Box 14)
    - AAGL Meet. Las Vegas, 11/8-11 '99, 1999 (Box 14)
    - Rotary 11/6-7 Myrtle Beach, 1998 (Box 14)
    - FAAGL 11/10, JAAGL 11/14, Atlanta GA, 1993-1998 (Box 14)
    - SLS [Society of Laparoendoscopic Surgeons] Dec. 9-12, San Diego, 1998 (Box 14)
    - AAGL Board, Jan. 4, 1994-1997 (Box 14)
    - JAAGL Jan. 5, 1996-1997 (Box 14)
    - [Loose records], 1997 and undated (Box 14)
    - Scottsdale Ab Providers, Mar 9-12 '97, 1996-1997 (Box 14)
    - Practical Training, Mar 12-15 '97, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Innerdyne, 1993-1995 (Box 14)
    - IPAS [empty folder] (Box 14)
    - Iron Intern, 1986-1992 (Box 14)
    - Innovative Projects (UNC-H), 1986-1991 (Box 14)
    - IUD and Sterilization, 1993 (Box 14)
    - INTRAH [International Training in Health], 1994 (Box 14)
    - J Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 14)
    - Denise Jamieson, Student, 1993 (Box 14)
    - Tammy Jenkins, CV, 1993-1995 (Box 14)
    - K Correspondence, 1978-1995 (Box 14)
    - Karman, Harvey (vacumm aspiration), 1982 (Box 14)
    - Kessel, Elton, 1993-1994 (Box 14)
    - Kim, Emily, 1990-1993 (Box 14)
    - King, Theodore M. - M.D., undated (Box 14)
    - Kjos, Siri, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Kleppinger, Richard K., M.D., 1980 (Box 14)
    - Knowles, Mike, M.D., 1987-1988 (Box 14)
    - James Kurtzman, M.D., 1992 (Box 14)
    - L Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 14)
    - [Loose records re. Law and Laparoscpoy] (Box 14)
    - Dr. Beverly R. Love, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Larsen vs. Neilson, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Connie Lefler, 1995 (Box 14)
    - Lefler, Hugh T. JR. M.D. and Hysteroscopy, 1987-1994 (Box 14)
    - Hugh Lefler, PMS study, 1993-1999 (Box 14)
  - Contents of Box 15: (Box 15)
    - B. Love - Office Endoscopy, 1993-1994 (Box 15)
    - Endo/Infert. Divisional Matters [empty folder] (Box 15)
    - Lessey, Bruce, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Lieff, Susan, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Lejeune, Camp, 1987-1990 (Box 15)
    - Legal Aspects of Tubal Sterilization, See Sterilization, legal... [empty folder] (Box 15)
    - Letters of Recommendation See: Recommendations, Letters of [empty folder] (Box 15)
    - Levin, Herbert, 1977-1984 (Box 15)
    - Lieberman, B.A., M.D. (clips), 1977-1997 (Box 15)
    - Life Insurance (absolute assignment), 1977-1978 (Box 15)
    - Lipkin, Mack M.D., 1986 (Box 15)
    - V. Lundstrom-Lindstedt, 1987-1995 (Box 15)
    - Lundstrom, Jan/Karolinska, M.D., 1987 (Box 15)
    - Lysis of Adhesions: Research Proposal, undated (Box 15)
    - Loffer, 1998 (Box 15)
    - M Correspondence, 1981-1990 (Box 15)
    - Mc Correspondence, 1981-1995 (Box 15)
    - Melanie MacLennan M.D., 1994-1995 (Box 15)
    - Male Infertility, 1975-1979, (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Malpractice Insurance, 1975-1976 (Box 15)
    - Marik, Jaroslav, M.D., 1975-1993 (Box 15)
    - Manuscripts Reviewed See: Papers reviewed [empty folder] (Box 15)
    - Markhart, Denise, 1979-1980 (Box 15)
    - Martin, Dan, M.D. re: Laser in Gyn, 1982-1996 (Box 15)
    - Lazar Marquies Mycoplasm Culture Media, 1977 (Box 15)
    - Mattox, Fleming see: Abortion '87 (JFH has entire paper) [empty folder] (Box 15)
    - Mazurek, Ruth (Academy of Health Sc. Sam Houston, TX), 1985 (Box 15)
    - Mead Johnson Laboratories' Medical Advisory Board, 1987-1992 (Box 15)
    - Medical Business, 1960-2003, (10 folders) (Box 15)
  - Contents of Box 16: (Box 16)
    - Medical Business: Photographs, 1979-1981 (Box 16)
    - Medical Business: Risk Management (malpractice), 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - Medical Business: Technical Assistance Information, 1985 (Box 16)
    - Medical Dynamics See: Bayne [empty folder] (Box 16)
    - Medical Malpractice (letter to legislators), 1987 (Box 16)
    - Medical Records, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Medical Music, 1981 (Box 16)
    - Med Peer Review Guidelines, 1976 (Box 16)
    - Medical Photographs, 1975-1976, undated (Box 16)
    - Med. Student Research, 1992 (Box 16)
    - Med. Students for Choice, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Mehra, M.D. See: Sterilization Reversibility [empty folder] (Box 16)
    - Mesrobian, Dr., 1995 (Box 16)
    - Microcircuitry and Ovulation Detection, 1981 (Box 16)
    - Microsurgery Fees, 1978-1980 (Box 16)
    - Microsurgical glasses See: Design for Vision [empty folder] (Box 16)
    - MFPP [Medical Faculty Practice Plan] Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 16)
    - Mohr, Kathleen, 1988-1989 (Box 16)
    - Unintended pregnancies in publicly financed maternity programs, undated (Box 16)
    - Morgan, Benjamin E., MD, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Myers, Evans, 1992 (Box 16)
    - MIUD, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Mumford, 1998 (Box 16)
    - [Loose record under N] (Box 16)
    - N Correspondence, 1980-1991 (Box 16)
    - NARAL, 1980-1995, (7 folders) (Box 16)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1962-1977, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Camran Nezhat, MD, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Nomenclature and Classification, 1982-1983 (Box 16)
    - North Carolina Memorial Endoscopy Suite, See: TV-1986 TV Teaching [empty folder] (Box 16)
    - Norway (Per Bordahl, MD), 1988 (Box 16)
    - November, Marty, 1991-1992 (Box 16)
  - Contents of Box 17: (Box 17)
    - Norplant, 1991-1993, (4 folders) (Box 17)
    - Omran, Kai, M.D., 1987-1999 (Box 17)
    - [Loose records under O] (Box 17)
    - O Correspondence, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Olympus Corporation, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Origin, Co., undated (Box 17)
    - Ovulation, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
    - P Correspondence, 1981-1999 (Box 17)
    - Pajor, Attila, 1994-1995 (Box 17)
    - Packard, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Pakistan Report '74, 1974 (Box 17)
    - Peterson, Bert, 1983-1989 (Box 17)
    - Peterson, Edwin, 1985 (Box 17)
    - Pfizer Hospital Products Group, See: FRG Notebook, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Pittsburgh, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Planned Parenthood, 1987-1990 (Box 17)
    - Poddar, Amal Kumar, M.D., 1969-1976, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Contents of Box 18: (Box 18)
    - Population Council, 1969-1980 (Box 18)
    - Population Services, Inc. (Population Council), 1970-1977 (Box 18)
    - Population Crisis Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 18)
    - Pajor, Dr. (see World Health Organization), [empty folder] (Box 18)
    - Penfield, A. Jefferson, See: Clip-Penfield, 1995-1996 (Box 18)
    - Pelvic Adhesions, 1986 (Box 18)
    - Pelvic Exam, See: Teaching Health Science Consort, Pelvic Exam [empty folder] (Box 18)
    - PID (Pelvic Inflamatory Disease) Management, 1987 (Box 18)
    - Jefferson Penfield, 1977-1986 (Box 18)
    - Pelvic Exam and Pap Smear See: TV [empty folder] (Box 18)
    - Pajor, Attila, M.D. See: WHO [empty folder] (Box 18)
    - Interesting Personnel Possibilities, 1980-1982 (Box 18)
    - Secretarial Position, 1970-1993 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous Personnel, 1969-1983 (Box 18)
    - Lee Wiggins, 1968-1976 (Box 18)
    - Omran, Dr. K.F., 1968-1984, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Mrs. Kathy Mohr, 1968-1975, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Prenancy - Adolescent, 1963-1987, (4 folders) (Box 18)
  - Contents of Box 19: (Box 19)
    - Pregnancy Testing, 1960-1971 (Box 19)
    - Preterm - a center for reproductive health, 1971-1981 (Box 19)
    - Price, Etheridge, Program Administrator Ob/Gyn, 1972-1980 (Box 19)
    - Psychiatry Department, 1969-1972 (Box 19)
    - Q Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 19)
    - Cystoscope Makers, Robert H. Quint, 1979 (Box 19)
    - R Correspondence, 1980-1996 (Box 19)
    - Ravnikar, Veronica, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Dr. Reich - Temp. Privileges, 1990-1995 (Box 19)
    - Reich, Harry, M.D. See: Laparascopy Textbook File, Special Techniques, 1988-1994 (Box 19)
    - Harry Reich, undated (Box 19)
    - Residents -- Residents Day '86, '87, '88, 1984-1990 (Box 19)
    - 1992 Residents Day, 1991-1992 (Box 19)
    - Resolve, Inc., 1979-1993 (Box 19)
    - Retirement, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Richard Wolf Co., See Laparoscopy Wolf Co. [empty folder] (Box 19)
    - Richardson, See: Gyn/Incontinence Surgery [empty folder] (Box 19)
    - Royalty Money, See: Grants, Active, 1988-1990 (Box 19)
    - Rock, John, M.D., 1987 (Box 19)
    - Clip Royalties, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Rosenberg, Jay Dr., 1995 (Box 19)
    - Royster, Vermont, 1987 (Box 19)
    - Rocket of London, 1980-1995 (Box 19)
    - RU 486, 1991 (Box 19)
    - Cefalo Sabbatical, 1988-1989 (Box 19)
    - Sabbatical Attempt 1983, 1983-1995 (Box 19)
    - Savitz, David A., PhD. (Nitrous Oxide Exposure...), 1987 (Box 19)
    - To: Dr. Hulka, From: Beverly Scarlett, 1992-1993 (Box 19)
    - Dr. Vicken Sahakian, 1992-1993 (Box 19)
    - Sandridge, David M.D., 1994 (Box 19)
    - Lillian Schapiro, 3rd yr PAP project, 1997 (Box 19)
  - Contents of Box 20: (Box 20)
    - Sex Determination, 1978-1981 (Box 20)
    - Siegler, Alvin, 1971-1987 (Box 20)
    - Sleep Deprivation, 1988 and undated (Box 20)
    - Sleep Study, 1987-1989 (Box 20)
    - Slides: Littering See: Teaching; Med. Stud. II [empty folder] (Box 20)
    - Slides (Misc.), 1982-1988 (Box 20)
    - Raleigh Women's Health Center, 1980-1995, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - [Loose records] (Box 20)
    - Resident's Day, 1990 (Box 20)
    - Bipolar Coagulation on Pigs, Dr. Rebecca Ryder, undated (Box 20)
    - Thad McDonald - Vaginal Hysterectomy, 1991 (Box 20)
    - Recommendation, Letters of (Sweeney), 1986 (Box 20)
    - Recommendation, Letters of Wilson, Joe, 1986 (Box 20)
    - Resident Research Day, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Resident's Day 1991, 1990-1994 (Box 20)
    - S Correspondence, 1980-1995 (Box 20)
    - Recommendation, Letters of (Misc.), 1984-1988 (Box 20)
    - Recommendation, Letters of: Hasson, 1987 (Box 20)
    - Recommendations: Spielman, M.D., 1987 (Box 20)
    - Sabbatical, undated (Box 20)
    - Sabbatical 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 20)
    - Snodgrass See: Wells, Ellen [empty folder] (Box 20)
    - Snow Job, 1978 (Box 20)
    - Soderstrom, M.D. See: Sterilization, Legal Aspects of Tubal, 1991-1993 (Box 20)
    - Southern Medical Journal, 1987-1988 (Box 20)
    - Spielman, M.D. (local anesthesia), 1982-1988 (Box 20)
    - Sperm Bank, 1993 (Box 20)
    - John Steege, M.D., undated (Box 20)
    - SRS Endometriosis, 1989 (Box 20)
    - Sterilization - Incentives for, undated (Box 20)
    - Sterilization Permit '88 Revision, 1988 (Box 20)
    - Sterilization, Legal Aspects of Tubal, 1988 (Box 20)
    - Sterilization: Planned Parenthood, 1987 (Box 20)
    - Sterilization (reversibility) (Dr. Mehra), 1980 (Box 20)
    - Sterilization Reversals, 1989 (Box 20)
    - Stevens, Holly 1992, 1992-1993 (Box 20)
    - The Stewart System, Laparoscopic Irrigator-Aspirator, undated (Box 20)
    - Stock, Richard, M.D., Magee-Womens Hospital, 1987 (Box 20)
    - Storz, Karl 1986 Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 20)
    - Student Research, 1990 (Box 20)
    - Stukes, Tom: Subchapter S. Corp., 1978 (Box 20)
  - Contents of Box 21: (Box 21)